Guide to the Prize Essay Collection, 1872-2017
Prize Essay Collection, 1872-2017
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Prize essay collection, 1872-2013
7-9-1317
Cornell University
8.4 cubic ft.
Manuscripts.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Prize-winning student essays from Cornell University contests in creative writing, poetry, social sciences, and humanities. Includes an essay on China by Pearl S. Buck.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Prize-winning student essays from Cornell University contests in creative writing, poetry, social sciences, and humanities. Includes an essay on China by Pearl S. Buck.
Note: The Corson Browning Prize, founded in 1902 by Professor Hiram Corson, and the Morrison Poetry Prize, founded in 1909 by James T. Morrison of Ithaca and continued for many years by Professor Morris Bishop, were combined in 1966 into the Corson-Bishop Poetry Prize.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Cornell University.; Bishop, Morris, 1893-1973.; Buck, Pearl S. (Pearl Sydenstricker), 1892-1973.; Cornell University.
Subjects:
Prizes.; Essays.; Literature--History and criticism.; College students--Poetry.
Places:
China--Description and travel.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. Arthur Lynn Andrews '93 Award for Creative Writing
Box 1
Series II. Barnes Shakespeare Prize
Boxes 2-3
Series III. Lt. David Chrystall Prize [1972]
Box 4
Series IV. Charles Lathrop Pack Foundation Forestry Prize
Box 5
Series V. Charles Lee Crandall Prize
Box 6
Series VI. Corson Browning Prize
Boxes 6-7
Series VII. Corson French Prize
Boxes 8-9
Series VIII. Corson Morrison Prize
Box 9
Series IX. Corson Bishop Poetry Prize
Box 9
Series X. Goethe Prize Essays
Boxes 9a, 32, 34
Series XI. Graduate Prize in Philosophy
Boxes 10-11
Series XII. The Guilford Prize
Boxes 12-14, 30
Series XIII. The Heermans Prize
Boxes 14-16
Series XIV. Mary B. Knoblaugh Prize
Box 16
Series XV. The Messenger Prize
Boxes 16-21
Series XVI Messenger-Chalmers Prize
Box 21
Series XVII. The Morrison Prize Poems
Box 22
Series XVIII. The Sherman Bennett Prize
Box 23
Series XIX. Sampson Fine Arts Competition
Item missing
Series XX. The Woodford Prize
Boxes 23-27
Series XXI. Unknown Prize
Box 27
Series XXII. Moses Coit Tyler Prize
Box 28
Series XXIII. Dorothy Sugarman Poetry Prize
Box 29
Series XXIV. Elmer Markham Johnson Prize
Box 29
Series XXV. Kasdan-Montessori Peace Prize
Boxes 29, 33
Series XXVI. Class of 1916 Prize
Box 31
Series XXVII. Douglas E. Whitney Prize
Box 28
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Arthur Lynn Andrews 1993 Award for Creative Writing
  - First Place, Louis Nayman (pseudonym P.F. Catcher), "A Failed Poet" (30 pp. Typescript and photocopies of other 3 stories submitted)., 1972 (Box 1)
  - Second Place, William Howard Mal (pseudonym Dee Speck), "The travelling Agricultural Implement Salesman and the Farmer's Daughter" (13 pp. Typescript)., 1972 (Box 1)
  - Two winners: Marian Novick (pseud. Andrea Linder) Five part Short Story, Part I "Minsk, 1909", Part II "Manhattan, 1919" etc.; Moe R. Muni (Pseud. For Scott R. Sommer) Three stories: "The Hollow", "The Night the Carousel Burned Down" and "Dimminck's Notebook", 1975 (Box 1)
  - First Place, Scott Ballotin (Arts '78) "Mrs. Levitan" (22 pp. Typescript), 1977 (Box 1)
  - First Place, Raphael Seligman (Arts '82) "See you later, Aleator" (28 pp. Typescript), 1981 (Box 1)
- Series II. The Barnes Shakespeare Prize
  - The Elizabethan Masque and the Masque Character of Shakespeare's Tempest and A Midsummer Night's Dream, by Walter C. Bronson, 1890 (Box 2)
  - Shakespeare's Nature Lines, by Oscar Diedrich von Engeln, 1905 (Box 2)
  - The Character of Ophelia, by John Bail, 1906 (Box 2)
  - Love Seen Through the Comic and the Tragic Spirit, as Illustrated by Benedick and Beatrice, Romeo and Juliet, by Alice W. Benham, 1907 (Box 2)
  - Shakespeare's Delineation of Insanity in King Lear, by H.M. Barr, 1908 (Box 2)
  - The Treatment and Significance of Shakespeare's Tragedy of Passion, by William Shea, 1909 (Box 2)
  - The Winter's Tale and Pandosto, How Shakespeare has Manipulated His Raw Material in Dramatizing the Story, by Charles Antoninus Carroll, 1910 (Box 2)
  - Shakespeare's Fools and Clowns, by Fred S. Kleinman, 1911 (Box 2)
  - Shakespeare's Richard II and Marlowe's Edward II - A Comparison, by Florence M. Carpenter, 1912 (Box 2)
  - Shakespeare's Hamlet - A Comparison with Kyd's Spanish Tragedy, by Miss Georgina Melville, 1913a (Box 2)
  - A Sojourn in the Primeval, by Mr. Harper - illustrative matter, 1913b (Box 2)
  - The Infinite Variety of Anthony and Cleopatra, by Colin A. H. Michael, 1914 (Box 2)
  - Certain Excellences in Othello, by John W. Jones, 1915 (Box 2)
  - The Macbeth of Shakespeare and the Agamemnon of Aeschylus, by Harry Caplan, 1916 (Box 2)
  - A Criticism of "Coriolanus," by Miss Eva M. Seeger, 1918 (Box 2)
  - The Last of the Ptolemies, by Rose S. Malmud, 1920 (Box 2)
  - The Mental Response to Shakespeare, by Laura Keane Zametkin, 1921 (Box 2)
  - Shakespeare, the Singer, by Desmond S. Powell, 1922 (Box 2)
  - Why consider Shakespeare?, by H. F. Cook, 1924 (Box 2)
  - The Supernatural Elements in The Tempest, 1925 (Box 2)
  - Shakespeare's Interpretation of Justice, by Margaret L. Plunkett, 1926 (Box 2)
  - The Women of Shakespeare's Coriolanus, by Frances M. Shattuck, 1927 (Box 2)
  - The Infinite Variety of Cleopatra, by William Maslow, 1929 (Box 2)
  - The Plutarchan Influence in Coriolanus, by George Simpson, 1930 (Box 2)
  - Richard of Gloucester in History and in Shakespearean Drama, by Harold A. Lehrman, 1931 (Box 2)
  - King Richard II, by Harold A. Segall, 1938 (Box 2)
  - Marcus Brutus, by Philip Cohen, 1939 (Box 3)
  - Shakespeare and the Aristotelian Tradition by John S. Lawrence, 1941 (Box 3)
  - Poetic Imagery in Richard II, by John H. Detmold, 1942 (Box 3)
  - Hamlet, a Revenge Tragedy, by Carla Small, 1943 (Box 3)
  - The Relation of Real Life and Fantasy in Shakespeare's Comedies, by Robert S. Bernen, 1949 (Box 3)
  - Some Remarks on King Lear, by Joanna Ruth Russ, 1957 (Box 3)
  - Plot Structure in "Romeo and Juliet" by Sharon Dee Solwitz, 1968 (Box 3)
  - On Pity in Hamlet, by David Ratner, n.d. (Box 3)
  - Disguise, Reason, and Truth in King Lear by Mel Behr ( Martha E. Linke ), 1971 (Box 3)
  - The Role of Edmund in "King Lear," by Jeremy Rabkin (First Prize), 1972 (Box 3)
  - Iago's Method: What Manner Poison for Othello's Ear, by L.M. Tozek (Second Prize), 1972 (Box 3)
  - Two winners: The Earl of Kent: Man in the Shadows by Susan Bianconi, Constructive Deception in As You Like It by Katharine Eisaman; 1975 (Box 3)
  - Voices of Secular Value: the Ghosts of Hamlet and Richard III, by Michael C. Berthold, 1977 (Box 3)
  - Walking About the Orb Like the Sun: The Role of the Wise Fools in Twelfth Night and King Lear by Susan J. Bianconi, 1978 (Box 3)
  - The Elements of Earth, Air, Water, and Fire in Antony and Cleopatra, by Charlotte Ram, April 15, 1980 (first prize) (Charlotte Ram pseud. For Leslie Camhi ), 1980 (Box 3)
  - The Role of Women in Hamlet by Ruth Watson, Arts & Sciences '83, 1982 (Box 3)
  - Readings of Shakespeare: Dissidence and the Merchant of Venice, by Nat Ives, May 1996, 1996 (Box 3)
- Series III. L. David Chrystall Prize
  - Winner Robert Alan Profusek '72 (pseudonym Francis Payne), "Image and Reality: An Analysis of the United States Decision-Making Process Which Led to the Initiation of the Program of Sustained Aerial Bombardment of North Vietnam, February 1965." (107 pp. photocopy), 1972 (Box 4)
  - Alison M. Dreizen, "Japanese-American Relations during the Nixon Administration". 110 pp. Mss., 1974 (Box 4)
  - Bradley Merrill Marten "A Divided Legacy" 72 pp. Mss., 1975 (Box 4)
  - Robert B. Bernstein '77, "The Collapse of the 1972 Soviet-American Trade Agreements", 1977 (Box 4)
- Series IV. The Charles Lathrop Pack Foundation Forestry Prize
  - The Forestry Idea, by John R. Curry, 1924 (Box 5)
  - Tom Jones Investigates Prosperity, by N. Gardner Bump, 1925 (Box 5)
  - Can Wood Substitutes Replace Our Daily Need for Wood?, by J. J. Wille, 1926 (Box 5)
  - The Autobiography of a White Pine, by Harold Pitt Smith, 1927 (Box 5)
  - Trade Extension in the Lumber Industry - Its Relation to the Promotion of Forestry Practice, by Charles E. McConnell, 1929 (Box 5)
  - DIXIE: The Land of Promise in Forestry, by Harold Gridley Wilm, 1930 (Box 5)
  - The Airplane, a New Tool in Forestry, by Darwin Miscall, 1931 (Box 5)
  - Scourge of American Forests, by John H. Eisinger, 1932 (Box 5)
  - A Federal Forestation Project for the Unemployed, by James D. Pond, 1933 (Box 5)
  - The Forestry Amendment to the Lumber Code, by Michel Afanasiev, 1934 (Box 5)
  - The Worth of the Civilian Conservation Corps, by John W. Humphreys, 1935 (Box 5)
  - The Question of Federal Ownership of Timberlands, by George Parsons, 1936 (Box 5)
  - Wood Needs No Defense, by Herbert J. Mols, 1937 (Box 5)
  - Forest Planting - An Essential Part of our Conservation Program, by Ellis F. Wallihan, 1938 (Box 5)
  - Foresty and Flood Control, by Ralph Resnick, 1940 (Box 5)
  - America's Forests: Now and After the War, by Earl Lewis Stone, Jr., 1942a (Box 5)
  - Possibilities of Rubber Production in South America, by Gaston Vivas-Berthier, 1942b (Box 5)
  - Forest Protection, by Ernestine Ann Rowlind, 1944 (Box 5)
  - Conservation or National Decline: America's Alternative, by Emmanuel Pollack, 1946 (Box 5)
  - This Concerns You, by Helen Ross, 1947 (Box 5)
  - Our Natural Heritage, by Daniel Duberman, 1948 (Box 5)
  - Land Use and Forestry in the Northeast, by Roland C. Clement, 1950 (Box 5)
  - We Must Keep Our National Forests, by George Burrows, 1953 (Box 5)
  - The Saving of Corkscrew Sanctuary, by Anne La Bastille, 1955 (Box 5)
  - This is Your State Forest, by John H. Kaufmann, 1956 (Box 5)
- Series V. The Charles Lee Crandall Prize
  - An Investigation of the Flow of Water in Wash Water Troughs for Rapid Sand Filters, by Frank Van Duzer Fields, 1918 (Box 6)
  - Investigation of the Flow of Water Through Submerged Diverging Tubes, by John Howard Stalker and Joseph Albert Thomas, 1920 (Box 6)
- Series VI. The Corson Browning Prize, Note: The Corson Browning Prize, founded in 1902 by Professor Hiram Corson, and the Morrison Poetry Prize, founded in 1909 by James T. Morrison of Ithaca and continued for many years by Professor Morris Bishop, were combined in 1966 into the Corson-Bishop Poetry Prize.
  - Browning as a Writer of Plays, by "John Dargan" ( J. Q. Adams, Jr. ), 1904 (Box 6)
  - Robert Browning as a Portrayer of the Spirit of the Renaissance, by Albert Davis, 1905 (Box 6)
  - Womanhood in Tennyson and in Browning, by Emma A. Miller, 1907 (Box 6)
  - The Ring and the Book as an Illustration of the Growth of Our Knowledge of Character, by "Richard Belmar" ( G. W. Nasmyth ), 1908 (Box 6)
  - The Treatment of Character in Browning's Dramas, by Marion Collins, 1909 (Box 6)
  - Browning and Italy, by Charles A. Carroll, 1910 (Box 6)
  - Browning's Treatment of External Nature, by Melvin G. Crowell, 1911 (Box 6)
  - Browning's Treatment of Judaism, by Harry M. Blank, 1912 (Box 6)
  - Browning's Conception of the Fine Arts, by Florence M. Carpenter, 1913 (Box 6)
  - A Defense of Browning's Optimism, by Suh Hu [ Hu Shih ], 1914 (Box 6)
  - Knowledge and Love as Treated in Paracelsus and Luria, by Victor H. Davis, 1915 (Box 6)
  - Browning's Ecclesiastics, by William E. Seely, 1916a (Box 6)
  - A Study of the Rhymes of Robert Browning, by Samuel Wilson, 1916b (Box 6)
  - Theories of Immortality in Browning's Poems, by Samuel Wilson, 1917 (Box 6)
  - Browning's Historical Portraits in "Parleyings with Certain People of Importance in Their Day," by Leah L. Lowensohn, 1920 (Box 6)
  - A Study of Browning's "Pauline," by Harold W. Blodgett, 1921 (Box 6)
  - The Development of Character in Paracelsus, by Malcolm L. Wilder, 1923 (Box 6)
  - Browning and Whitman, by Vivan Earl Simroll, 1924 (Box 6)
  - Browning's Narrative Art, by Henry F. Cook, 1925 (Box 7)
  - The Grotesque in Browning, by Mary Lynch Johnson, 1926 (Box 7)
  - Browning's Portrait of Paracelsus, by William Benedict, 1929 (Box 7)
  - Browning's Treatment of Romantic Love as a Motive, by Herbert Brodsky, 1930 (Box 7)
  - Prince Hohenstiel-Schwangau, a Study in the Rhetoric of Poetry, by J. B. Emperor, 1932 (Box 7)
  - The Jew in Browning's Poetry, by Florence M. Hoagland, 1933 (Box 7)
  - Browning and Euripides, by Argus John Tresidder, 1934 (Box 7)
  - "Strafford," One Hundred Years After: An Autopsy, by Christopher Morley, Jr., 1937 (Box 7)
  - Browning's Treatment of Evil, by Margaret A. Kirkwood, 1943 (Box 7)
  - Mr. Browning in Browning's Poetry, by Ruth L. Bayless, 1945 (Box 7)
  - Obscurity in the Poetry of Robert Browning, by Jan W. Dietrichson, 1949 (Box 7)
  - The Theatre of Alfred de Musset, by "Alfred Page", 1951 (Box 7)
- Series VII. The Corson French Prize
  - The Influence of Spain upon French Seventeenth Century Literature, by Arthur Gordon, 1908 (Box 8)
  - Autobiographical Elements in Paul Verlaine's Poetry, by George Irving Dale, 1909 (Box 8)
  - A Comparison of Racine's Phedre with Euripides' Hippolytus and Seneca's Phaedra, by Roger G. Manube, 1911 (Box 8)
  - Pierre Bayle, Forerunner of the Philosophes, by Bleeker Marquette, 1912 (Box 8)
  - The Cosmopolitanism of Mme. De Stael, by Grace Marcus, 1914 (Box 8)
  - Memoires D'Outre Tombe, by Miss S. K. Toksvig, 1915 (Box 8)
  - Du Bellay in Rome, by Charlotte Helen Pekary, 1916 (Box 8)
  - Montaigne and Renan, by Leslie C. Schwartz, 1917 (Box 8)
  - Voltaire's English Letters, by George William McDonald Robertson, 1918 (Box 8)
  - The Drama of Rostand, by Leah L. Lowensohn, 1919 (Box 8)
  - Pierre de Ronsard in 1924, by Miss Vera L. Peacock, 1924 (Box 8)
  - Montaigne's Theories of Education in the American College, by H. M. Peavy, 1925 (Box 8)
  - The Greek Tradition in the Work of Albert Samain, by Miss Anna Gasool, 1927 (Box 8)
  - An Estimate of Musset's Lorenzaccio, by E. E. Pope (that's Miss), 1928 (Box 8)
  - Ideas of Houdar de la Motte on Poetry, by Herbert Brodsky, 1929a (Box 8)
  - Julien Green, Novelist Psychiatric, by H. Weiss, 1929b (Box 8)
  - Le Roman Contemporain, by Volkoff, 1930 (Box 8)
  - The Poetry of Paul Verlaine, by Abraham Schultz, 1931a (Box 8)
  - Madame Bovary, Soixante-Dix Ans Apres, by Perry Cornell Dechert, 1931b (Box 8)
  - Andre Gide, by Hyman Yudewitz, 1932 (Box 8)
  - What Did Voltaire Get From England?, by Nobuko Takagi, 1933 (Box 8)
  - Emerson & Montaigne, by Keith W. Johnson, 1934 (Box 8)
  - The Origin and Development of the Opera Comique in France, by Harold E. Johnson, 1937 (Box 8)
  - Villon: The Fact and the Legend, Rose Ransom, 1938 (Box 8)
  - The Origins of the Chansons de Geste, by Robert M. Hankin, 1941 (Box 9)
  - A Study of the Life and Works of the Baron D'Holbach, by Joseph Sbunsky, 1942 (Box 9)
  - The Origins of the Chansons de Geste, by Dorothy Socolow, 1944 (Box 9)
  - Poe in France, by Harry G. Edwards, 1947 (Box 9)
  - Andre Gide: Works and Main Ideas on the Background of his Life, by Jan W. Dietrichson, 1948 (Box 9)
  - Origins of the Chansons de Geste, by George A. Hazen, 1949 (Box 9)
  - The Influence of Rousseau's Childhood on His Educational Theories by Carol Bagger [Xanthippe OLeary], 1949 (Box 9)
  - Le Vie de la Cour vue par Mme. De Sevigne, by Mahdi S. Elmandjra, 1954 (Box 9)
  - The Turbulent Life of the Abbe Prevost, by Clifford S. Leonard, 1956 (Box 9)
- Series VIII. Corson-Morrison Poetry Prize
  - "9 Poems" by John Latta '75 (pseudonym P.Q. Reegan), 1972 (Box 9)
- Series IX. Corson-Bishop Poetry Prize (name change 1975), Note: The Corson Browning Prize, founded in 1902 by Professor Hiram Corson, and the Morrison Poetry Prize, founded in 1909 by James T. Morrison of Ithaca and continued for many years by Professor Morris Bishop, were combined in 1966 into the Corson-Bishop Poetry Prize.
  - Two winners: Thomas Johnson: "Some Lines for a Cathedral Bell Past Midnight and Other Poems"; Ross Tharaud: "Meditation and Other Poems", 1975 (Box 9)
  - "The Quarry" and 5 other poems by Robert Dale Schultz, grad. student, 1976 (Box 9)
  - Mark Anderson, co-winner, 1978 (Box 9)
  - James B. Hathaway, co-winner, 1978 (Box 9)
  - Alice Fulton, graduate, co-winner, 1981 (Box 9)
- Series X. Goethe Prize Essays
  - "Lessing's Dramas" by Karen Elise Monrad, 1906 (Box 9a)
  - "Goethe's Rule of Life As It Appears In His Poems" by Miss M. E. Farr, 1920 (Box 9a)
  - "Der Junge Goethe, 1770-1775" by William Holderman (In German), 1921 (Box 9a)
  - "Goethe, the Man as Revealed in his Letters" by L. Grossfeld, 1922 (Box 9a)
  - "Goethe's Humanism" by I. Awoki, 1925 (Box 9a)
  - Goethe's "Werther" as a record of Experience and as a Work of Art by Elfrieda E. Pope, 1927 (Box 9a)
  - Goethe, Poet of the Soul, by Harold G. Carlson, 1928 (Box 9a)
  - "The Personality of Goethe As Revealed in His Letters" by Harold D. Feuerstein, 1929 (Box 9a)
  - A Comparison of Goethe's Faust Part I with the Urfaust and the Fragment by, "Merlin", 1931 (Box 9a)
  - "The Young Goethe - 1770-1775" by P. Nevin, pseud. Hyman Yudewitz, 1932 (Box 9a)
  - "Goethe's Rule of Life as it Appears in his Poems" by Miss Helen Bretstein ('36), 1936 (Box 9a)
  - "Autobiography and Poetry in Werther" by A. Ames, 1941 (Box 9a)
  - "Goethe's Idea of Religious Tolerance As Compared With That of the Enlightenment" by Beatrice Gottlieb ('45), 1944 (Box 9a)
  - "Goethe and Carlyle" by Pobeda MacLachlin, 1954 (Box 9a)
  - "Humor and Satire in Goethe's Faust" by Richard Hyde Kerr [NB: this topic was among those set in 1945 and 1954 as well as in 1958, and it is possible that Kerr submitted his essay in any one of these years--in the absence of evidence of when he studied here], 1958 (Box 9a)
  - "Is There Justification for Goethe's title: Faust, eine Tragödie" by "Ricarda" (In German), 1959 (Box 9a)
  - "Swine, Therefore, Shall Ye Become: A Discussion of the Circe Legend in Faust, Part I" by Basya-Marie Romanoff, 1965 (Box 9a)
  - "Form and Meaning in Goethe's 'Dauer im Wechsel'" by Timothy C. Plowman ('66), 1966 (Box 9a)
  - "Tieck's Use of Lyric in Der schönen Magelone" by Walter L. Knorr (grad.), 1967 (Box 9a)
  - " 'Siguen Auf Der Linde' (Parzival 249, 11 ff.) And the Turtle-Dove" by Arthur B. Groos, Jr. (Grad.), 1968 (Box 9a)
  - Arnim's "Die Majoratsherren": Its Romantic Elements by Mary Ann Copeland (pseudonym Vitzli Putzli), 1970 (Box 9a)
  - Prinz Friedrich von Homburg: an Interpretation by Paul David Hobbs (pseudonym Paul Grayson), 1970 (Box 9a)
  - Franz Kafka: Ein Altes Blatt - Versuch einer Deutung by Anja Hugel, 18 pp. (In German), 1971 (Box 9a)
  - "By Water and By Fire" Second Place (no first place awarded). 12 pp. by Barry Michael Laine ('72)., 1972 (Box 9a)
  - "Poet and Poetic Process in the Narrative Framework of C.F. Meyer's 'Die Hochzeit des Monchs'," by William D. Wilson., 1975 (Box 9a)
  - "Kafka's Der Prozess: the Problem Of Interpretation" by David Vierling 20 pp. Photocopy., 1976 (Box 9a)
  - First prize:"Der Eregire, Lantlose Tristan": The Development of the Hero in Gottfried's Tristan, by Michael W. Twomey, grad. student. 29 pp. photocopy, 1977 (Box 9a)
  - Second prize: "Adalbert Stifter: Die Formulierung und Realisierung siener Kunstauffassung in den Bunten Steinen" by Valerie Rynne, grad. student. 16 pp. Photocopy., 1977 (Box 9a)
  - Third prize: "Formula, Style and Structure in the Nibelungenlied", written by Rudy Spraycar, grad. student. 21 pp. Photocopy., 1977 (Box 9a)
  - "Sunrise and the Griffon: Wolfram's Dawn Song Sine klawen" by H. Peiromene ( Mary F. Wack ), 1979 (Box 9a)
  - "A Short Guided Tour Through Friedrich Schlegel's Philosophy of Art" by Ifsan Sorbutts ( Peter Simpson, grad student, May 2, 1980), 1980 (Box 9a)
  - "Sprachlandschaft" by Daniel J. Kane, graduate student in Germanic studies. 20 pp. photocopy, 1981 (Box 32)
  - "Eulogy of a Lost Cause: Heine's 'Ludwig Marcus' " by Catherine Creecy, graduate student in German Literature. 20 pp., 1982 (Box 9a)
  - "Die Rose Schönheit Soll Nicht Sterben": Celan's Translations of Shakespeare's Sonnets by I. Zensen (Graduate) [ Claire Oshetsky, Dept. of Modern Languages & Linguistics], 1983 (Box 9a)
  - "Zu: Irmtraud Morgners Leben und Abenteuer der Trobadora Beatriz nach Zeugnissen ihrer Speilfrau Laura: Mutproben und Ansatzpunkte zur Trobadora Beatriz nach spielerischen Zeugnissen ihrer Leserin Meta" von Meta Morphose ( Suzanne Rohr, graduate student), 1984 (Box 32)
  - Wîp and Grâl and the Bipartite Structure of Parzival's Book IV by Paul Warren ( Kevin Marti, graduate student), 1985 (Box 32)
  - Bildungsroman: An Unfulfilled Genre? ( Andrew Hewitt, Graduate) [A. Wright], 1986 (Box 32)
  - Thoughts on Kretzschmar, Beethoven, and Doctor Faustus ( Steven Bilecka ), 1988 (Box 32)
  - Adorno's "The Aging of the New Music" as a Political Theory of Criticism, by Arthur C. T. Strum, 1990 (Box 32)
  - Conflict, Collective Action and the Life Chances of Ethnic Organizations: German Newspapers in Chicago, 1846-1956, August Spies [ Elizabeth West ], 1991 (Box 32)
  - "Do wuohs in Niderlander eins edelen kuneges kint": Siegfried and Duby's Paradigm of the 12th Century Aristocratic Youth, David F. Johnson, 1992 (Box 32)
  - "Wenn du geredet hattest, Desdemona": Die Roll von Milleilung und die Macht von Sprechen, Ariel O. Morgan ( Toni J. Querry ), 1993 (Box 32)
  - Language and the Mechanics of Presence in Herder's Plastik, Robert Wallace ( John R. Crutchfield ), 1996 (Box 32)
  - The 'New Ethic' and its Danger by Helen Stocker ( Tracie Matysik ), 2000 (Box 32)
  - The Significance of Life: The Unity of Hegel's Dialectic of Self-Consciousness by John Namjun Kim, 2000 (Box 32)
  - Good or Evil?: The Impact of Thought on Society as Interpreted from Hoffman's The Golden Pot and The Sandman, by Jessica Lammers, 2001 (Box 32)
  - Mental Division Between Man and Insect, by Esther Livingstone, 2001 (Box 32)
  - Of Death, Kitsch, and Melancholia: Aimee und Jaguar, by Anna Parkinson, 2001 (Box 32)
  - Kant's Judgment of Music ( Contrary to All Experience), by Marianne Tettlebaum, 2001 (Box 32)
  - The Intangible Effects of One's Faith, by Jamie Wainstock, 2001 (Box 32)
  - Second prize, freshman/sophomore: An Autopsy of Memory: a Discussion of Daniel Libeskind's Jewish Museum Extension to the Berlin Museum, by "Jonathan", 2002 (Box 32)
  - Second prize, freshman/sophomore: Verwirrungen, by Melissa Jones, 2002 (Box 32)
  - Second prize, junior/senior: The Time and Place of Modernity, by Alice Carey, 2002 (Box 32)
  - First prize, graduate: On German Musical Conversations: The Allgemeine musikalische Zietung and the Ideas of "True" String Quartets ca. 1800, by "P.", 2002 (Box 32)
  - Second prize, graduate: Subjectivity in Sartre's Works and Rilke's Notebooks of Malte Laurids Brigge, by Patricia O'Leary, 2002 (Box 32)
  - Family Disputes: Tensions in Hegel's Conception of the Family Ryan Plumley, 2003 (Box 32)
  - A Summary Approach to Kafka's 'Das Urteil' Josh Dittrich, 2003 (Box 32)
  - Vicissitudes of Choice Anstasia Pouchkareva, 2003 (Box 32)
  - A Fairy Tale Come True Lindsay Wilczynski, 2003 (Box 32)
  - Second place Freshmen/Sophomore: Melancholia and Self-Reflexive Realities in Goethe's "Faust" Trevor Miller, 2004 (Box 32)
  - First place, graduate: Oswald Egger's Poetry of Birds, Beasts and the Art of Beholding or, Poetic Augury in the Utter Zoo of Semiotics Samuel Frederick, 2004 (Box 32)
  - Second place, graduate: Konvention als Kritik? Mozarts 'klavier sonate mit begleitung einer Violin, KV 526 Wiebke Thormahlen, 2004 (Box 32)
  - Second place, graduate: Bewegung' and Ruhrung': Musikspielende Androide und die Schnittpunkte ihrer kulturellen Bedeutungen im spaten 18. Jahrhundert in Deutschland Adelheid Voskuhl, 2004 (Box 32)